<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>GitHub</u>

# J.R. Muri

Front-end Web Developer

Calgary | #403-973-6873 | julesrubies@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

J.R. is a front-end web developer with a strong focus on UI and UI components. Coming from 5 years of customer service roles and 3 years as a professional photographer, and over the past year, studying the discipline of web development. He has a strong overlap of interpersonal, creative, and technical skills to leverage in favor of modern tech environments.

# **SKILLS**

• Technologies: HTML5, CSS3/Sass, JavaScript, Node.JS

• Frameworks: Vue

• Tools: Adobe Suite, Figma, Visual Studio Code, Git

• Database: MongoDB/Mongoose

• Deployment: Docker

Concepts: Responsive design, REST API

# **EDUCATION**

# Web Development Certification — SAIT Polytechnic

January 2020 - July 2020

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

#### **Core Concepts:**

- Web Design Theory, Tools & Technique
- Web Client & Server Programming
- WordPress & CMS Systems

- Social Media & Marketing
- E-Commerce
- Deployment

Web Development Certification – Mount Royal University

January 2018 - May 2018

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Chemical Laboratory Technologies Diploma — SAIT Polytechnic

September 2007 - June 2010

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Calefy — Student Developer

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

May 2020 - July 2020

- Developed and implemented stateful reusable UI components in dynamic form building software
- Worked in a codebase including a spread of languages, libraries and frameworks, most relevant being: React,
  Redux, Material-UI, and Informed on the front-end, with Python, Django, GraphQL and APollo on the back-end
- Engaged in live component user/usability testing and evaluation from marketing team

# Jules Ruby Photography — Event Photographer

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

August 2016 - PRESENT

### **PROJECTS**

## Hypothetical Shopping App

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Python + Flask, Vue + Vuetify + Bootstrap Vue, Stripe

**Scope**: Collaborate with two others to build a proof-of-concept CRUD web app for a local table-top game shop. Creating a better way for the business to process online transactions for product rentals. Project was built using Vue to create the client-facing SPA, which made API calls to the Python-Flask back end for the stored product data, and to Stripe for transactions.

#### Pokemon API

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, REST API, Git

**Scope**: Create client-facing application to fetch data from an open-source API, and use the returned values to dynamically generate a web page in the browser. Displaying the requested information in organized card based panels, which also act as navigable links which lead to more detailed fetch information.

#### SASS Library

Technologies: HTML5, CCS3, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, Git

**Scope**: Collaborate with a group to plan and design a news website mockup. Then, divide the work up and develop a library of SASS variables and mixins to streamline the process of making site-wide style shifts, ensuring code is reusable.

#### Custom Gallery Website

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, EJS, MongoDB, Heroku, Git

**Scope**: Develop and deploy a static website using EJS to template it, so that it can easily generate new content as it is added to the database. This web site's primary feature is the custom image gallery, which showcases the power of the templating engine to draw from stored data.